Daniel Mário de Lima, 29

São Carlos, SP, Brazil

+55 16 98832 3661 https://limadm.github.io/ danielmariodelima@gmail.com

Systems Analyst, M.Sc. degree in Computer Science by the Institute of Mathematical and Computer Sciences (ICMC) of the University of São Paulo at São Carlos, Brazil. Proficient programmer and fast learner, with experience in several areas: software engineering, databases, distributed systems, networking, embedded systems, data mining, information visualization and machine learning. Currently researching deep learning applications for healthcare systems.

Education

PhD student in Computer Science, ICMC / USP (2017 – present)

Concentration Areas: Databases, Visualization, Deep Learning.

M.Sc. in Computer Science, ICMC / USP (2011 – 2013)

Concentration Areas: Databases, Visualization, Graph Theory and Applications.

Specialist in Computer Networks, UESPI (2010, interrupted)

B.Tech. in Information Systems, IFPI (2006 – 2008)

Certifications

Certified Tester Foundation Level, ISTQB (2009)

Experience

Researcher and Software Developer at São Carlos. (Mar. 2011 – present)

Database systems and Linux administration, web / mobile development (RESTful APIs + Web and Android endpoints), distributed computing, distributed NoSQL databases, circuit design for embedded systems in industrial automation and remote sensing, software development for microcontrollers and single board computers (Arduino, AVR, PIC and Raspberry Pi), data mining (cleaning, filtering, transformation and feature mapping), computer vision (OCR, object detection and classification, GUI automation) and machine learning (statistical methods and neural networks).

Teaching Assistant at ICMC / USP, São Carlos. 6h/week. (Aug. 2012 – Dec. 2012) Course: Database Practice I. M.Sc. curricular component.

Software Developer at Infoway, Teresina. 44h/week. (Apr. 2009 – Jan. 2011)

Design and development of a complete ERP system (for a cooperative of anesthesiologists) and its proprietary web MVC framework. Written in Java using Struts and Hibernate.

Skills

Popular methods and tools:

- Project Management, Security and Quality Assurance (Testing / Integration);
- C11, C++17, ES6, Java8, Python, Ruby, and their ecosystems;
- MySQL, Oracle and PostgreSQL databases;
- Django, Hibernate / Spring, Rails and MEAN stacks;
- Android SDK / NDK and Haxe mobile development;
- Maven, VirtualEnvs, LXC, Docker and other deployment approaches;

Specialized technologies:

- Hadoop and EC2 distributed computing;
- Cassandra and S3 distributed storage;
- Tarantool distributed storage and application server;
- HTML5 / CSS3, SVG, WebGL and D3.js for rich UIs and visualizations;
- CL, LuaJIT, Matlab / Octave, OpenMP, Orange, R, SageMath and many others;
- Caffe, TensorFlow, Torch and other machine learning / optimization libraries.

Traits

Careful thinking, pragmatic development and objective communication;

Friendly, open-minded, adaptable to changes, teamworker, perfectionist, achiever, resilient;

Hobbies: DIY, science, drama, exotic cultures, hiking and cycling.